

CONTACT

Venloer Str., 50825 Köln

Portforlio | LinkedIn

SKILLS

- Robotics: ROS2, YOLO
- Industrial Communication:
 Modbus, CAN, IO-Link
- SysML
- Industrial Automation & Control
- Prototyping: FDM, SLA
- Project Management

PROGRAMMING

- C/C++
- Python
- ST
- MATLAB

SOFTWARE

- Arduino, VS Code
- Linux (Ubuntu)
- CODESYS, TIA portal
- Solidworks, Inventor, AutoCAD, NX, Fusion

LANGUAGES

- German (B1)
- English (Fluent)
- Thai (Native)

HOBBIES

- Reading
- Fitness, tennis, badminton
- Guitar

PANITHI THUNGKAO

PROFILE

Master's student in Mechatronics Engineering at FH Aachen with a strong interest in robotics, AI, industrial automation, and project management. Keen on applying systems engineering principles following the V-model. Familiar with SysML and experienced in interdisciplinary development workflows.

EDUCATION

FH-Aachen, Germany

2024 - PRESENT

Master in Mechatronics Engineering

- Project Robotics—Object-Tag Mapping in a Simulated Warehouse with ROS2
- Project Industrial Communication—Integrating/debugging sensors using protocols like Modbus, CAN, and IO-Link—following OSI-ISO model
- Project Mechatronic Systems—Automation of Go-Cart partnering with ifm
 - Integrated ifm Safety PLC (CR701S), Joystick (CR1301), BOSCH BLDC Motor with CODESYS. Designed the electric driving system, ensuring cost-effectiveness and budget compliance—following the V-model (VDI/VDE 2206) aimed to comply with EU Normatives.
- Tutor for ROS Summer School

• Hochschule Rhein-Waal, Germany

2019 - 2023

Bachelor in Mechatronic Systems Engineering

- **Project: Autonomous Cleaning Mobile Robot**: led a team. The project was selected for publication.
- Bachelor Thesis: designed a solution for 3D-printed violin with the goal to minimize cost to quality (FDM, Low Force Stereolithography)

WORK EXPERIENCE

Fiverr (Freelance)

2024 - PRESENT

Mechatronic Systems Engineer

- Designing product: CAD models, BOM, and technical documentation.
- Robotic Simulation with ROS2

Outlier Al

2024 - PRESENT

Al Training Conductor - Mathematic

Rocket Factory AG, Augsburg, Germany Mechatronics and Hardware Electronics Intern

2022 - 2023

- Developed testing equipment and methods for battery modules designed as main power for electronics in rocket stages, improving testing efficiency.
- Prototyped using Raise3D N2+ 3D-printer and assisted in CAD modeling and assembly of Li-ion battery modules.

FH Aachen, Jülich

2018-2019

Engineering Intern

- Conducted metalworking, woodworking and mechanical assembly.
- Conducted electrical hardware testing and circuit design.
- Technical programming in python, HTML, CSS, JavaScript